Considering the ever-increasing medical conditions in India, it
seems that
after crossing a particular age, we must have
a critical illness policy.
Upon diagnosis of the critical illnesses listed in a critical illness policy, the policyholder receives a lump sum
compensation, meaning the
entire sum insured is
given to them so that they can get treatment for this critical illness. In
most critical
illness plans, the list
of critical illnesses is quite small,
but there is also a plan in which you
can get coverage for 100 critical illnesses within a single
plan. The name of this plan is TA
AIG Critical Medicare Plan.
What are the eligibility conditions for taking this plan, that is,
who can take this plan? There are a
total of three sections given in this plan through which
you can get different coverages.
What are their benefits and what are the coverages, we will
learn about them in today's video and critical
illness.  Along with the coverage of
cancer treatment can also be covered under this policy, we will
also know which option we will have to choose for that,
apart from this, an optional section has also been given separately in
which some surgeries will be covered,
which are those surgeries and what is the
benefit of this section, we will also know that, that is,
we will review the Tata AIG Criti Medicare Plan in detail in today's video,
so if you are looking for
a critical illness policy for yourself or any member of your family, then you must understand the
Tata AIG
Criti Medicare Plan once, let's
not delay and
quickly start this video, you get a total of three sections
under the Tata AIG Criti Medicare Plan,
section A will
cover critical illness, that is,
serious diseases will be covered under section A,
section B will cover cancer
treatment, that is why the name of this section is
Cancer 360° and section C will cover
hospital cash, that is, for the number of days the patient is
admitted, apart from the cost of treatment,
they do not get any other benefits.  Extra daily cash benefit will
also be available, it will be covered under Section C.
Apart from these three, there is an optional Section
B. Section D, which is a benefit from well-sure,
covers some surgeries.
So, these four sections are in total
within it. We will understand the benefits of all these sections in
detail, but
first let us discuss the eligibility conditions for taking them. The
first condition in the eligibility for taking this plan is the
entry age, that is, what will be the minimum and
maximum entry age? If you
want to take coverage of Section A, that is, critical
illness,
then the entry age will be from
minimum 18 years to maximum 65 years. If
you want coverage of Section B, in which
cancer treatment will be covered, then the minimum
age will be from 91 days to 65 years. If you
want to take hospital cash benefit, then
also the minimum age will be 91 days and the
maximum age limit is 65 years. And if you want
optional  If you choose Section D for benefits, the
minimum entry age is 18
years, and the maximum entry age is 65 years.
You must take this policy within this age group,
whichever section you choose for your coverage.
Now comes the turn to discuss the plan type,
meaning what kind of policy you
can take. Here you have two
options available: an individual plan.
You can take this if you want to take a policy for yourself.
If you want to add other family members
to this policy,
you will have to take separate sum insured for each member, that is,
you can take a multi-individual policy.
Because a critical illness diagnosis will provide
coverage to only one specific member, so
you will have to choose the sum insured for each member separately.
Now, let's talk about the tenure, that is,
how long a policy you can take together. You can choose
this Critical Medicare plan for 1 year, 2 years, or 3 years
if
you take a long-term policy.  If you take a policy for 2 years,
you get a long term discount of 5%
and if you take a policy for 3 years,
you will get a long term policy
discount of 10%. There is no age limit on how long you can renew this plan.
You can renew this policy for life long,
but while entering, keep in
mind that
you will have to choose this plan only after the entry ages have been mentioned. Now,
because there is coverage for critical illnesses, there
is coverage for serious diseases and the sum insured can
also be large, will any policy
holder have to undergo a medical checkup for
this? The company has defined criteria for this.
If you take coverage under Section A,
under which you get coverage for critical illnesses
and the policyholder's age is
more than 46 years, then the insurance company can
arrange for a medical checkup. Now,
who will pay for this expense? If the insurance company
accepts your proposal, that is, it
is ready to give you the policy, then the
insurance company will bear half the money of this medical expense
and we will have to pay the other half.
Apart from this, whatever the age group, sum insured
or coverage of any different section,
For this, there can be telemedical in which
your medical conditions can be asked over the phone.
After discussing the eligibility conditions, now comes the turn to understand the coverage of all the sections.
First of all, we will discuss Section A,
under which
you will get coverage for critical illness. So the first point is
how much coverage of sum insured can
we take here. The minimum option for this
is ₹ lakh and the maximum
sum insured up to ₹ crore. You can choose for the coverage of Section A.
As you know, there is coverage of critical illness in Section A.
So, giving some flexibility here, the
insurance company has given you two options. The
first choice is Smart Century
Premier Plan, under which
you will get coverage for 100 critical illnesses and the second
plan is Smart Half Century Plan,
under which you can get coverage for 50 critical illnesses.
Under Section A,
you will have to choose this one section while buying the policy.
Whichever variant you choose from this, the same
number will be there.  These critical
illnesses will be covered in your plan. The
complete list of these 50 and 100 critical illnesses
is given in the PDF of the plan's policy words and
I have given the link of this PDF for you
in the description of this video.
After watching this video, you can click on it and
see and review all the critical illnesses
and decide whether
you want to take the Smart Century
Premier Plan or the Smart Half
Century Plan. The
next coverage you get in Section A is for health checkup
which is the sum assured of your previous policy, that is,
when you renew the policy,
you will get the facility of health checkup only after a maximum block of ₹1000000,
under Section A. Smart
Cancer Care is also a part of the coverage of Section A. However,
if
any listed critical illness
is diagnosed under Section A, then whatever sum
insured we have chosen, the insurance company
gives the entire amount to the policy holder.
Smart Cancer Care says that if
cancer is diagnosed, then apart from that amount,
you can also claim some extra money from the company.
It will depend on the
stage of cancer diagnosed.
If it is stage one cancer, then 20% of the sum
insured can be claimed.
If second stage cancer is
diagnosed, then 30% of the sum insured
and if third stage cancer is
diagnosed, then up to 50% of the sum insured can be
claimed separately.
This is over and above sum insured, that is, it is in
addition to the sum insured for the critical illness you have chosen. If
cancer is diagnosed, then
you will also get the facility of second medical opinion under Section A. That is, if
any of the listed critical illnesses is
diagnosed, then you can consult the panel
hospitals, network practitioners or
doctors about what
kind of treatment you should take and whether the treatment
you are receiving will be of any benefit.  Related: You
can take a second opinion from a doctor
without any extra cost. Waiver of
premium: If a policy holder is
diagnosed with a critical illness and the
insurance company accepts a claim, then the
premium of Rs. 70 for the next three years will be waived. If a
policy holder was paying ₹1000000 as premium, then
he will have to pay only ₹33000 for the next three
years. The waiver of
premium option is
available only within the Smart Century Premier Plan, that is, the
premium will be waived in the same plan in which you get coverage for 100 critical illnesses. Now, generally, in
critical illness policies,
if a claim is made once, the
policy ends there itself. The policy is
discontinued. The company has paid the claim and the
policy will not be valid further. But this is not the case in this policy
because you
also get the facility of multiple insurance under this policy
because there are three sections in this policy. One claim from each of the
three is accepted in lifetime.  You
can take it, that is, after one claim, your
policy will not be discontinued; the rest of the
policy of these two sections will continue as it is. The
survival period is also a very important
point, that is, once a policy
holder is diagnosed with a critical illness,
then for
how many days he must survive to be eligible for the claim,
this is also the choice given to us by the insurance company -
zero days, seven days and 15 days.
Whichever choice we make of survival
period, any policy holder will be able to get the claim
only after surviving for that much time.
Whatever coverage I have told you under section A
is related to the listed critical illness and for the list, you have to
refer to which worlding, keep this in
mind. Now we will discuss section B,
under which
we can cover cancer treatment and the name of this section is
Cancer 360°, that is, this section will provide coverage to cancer from all sides.
First of all, let us know about the sum assured.
For cancer treatment,
from ₹ lakh to  A sum assured of up to ₹ crore can be
chosen for Section B. The
first coverage in this segment is for
hospitalization treatments.
This sum assured can be used for any type of treatment after a cancer diagnosis.
This Section B will provide
coverage to the policyholder for this. Apart from this, there is
DK treatment, i.e.,
treatment for which admission is not necessary.
If any day care procedure related to cancer is required, then
this plan will cover that as well. The
facility of home care treatment
is also available under Section B. That is, if
a policyholder who has been diagnosed with cancer
wants to get treatment at home after the approval of the insurance company, then
they will get coverage for that as well under Section B.
Chemotherapy and radiotherapy, since these are
related to cancer treatment, will
also be covered under Section B.
Coverage of advanced treatments, i.e., modern treatments, will be available in this section. Of
course, these listed modern
treatments, which are visible on the screen right now,
if they are used for cancer treatment, then the
policyholder will definitely get coverage for them under Section B.
Apart from this, high-end diagnostic
Coverage of Rs. 10000 will also be available under Section B. If
after cancer diagnosis, some high-end
diagnostic tests have to be done as OPD, then there will be an
annual limit of Rs. 25,000
for high-end diagnostic tests
if these are part of cancer treatment
and these tests can also be done as OPD.
Psychiatric counselling is also
covered under Section B.
After cancer diagnosis, if a policy
holder faces trauma and has to
take psychiatric counselling, then
₹2000000 is covered for eight counselling sessions. Pre and post
hospitalisation expenses: If the
patient is admitted for cancer treatment, then 60
days of pre-hospitalisation and 90 days of
post-hospitalisation i.e. expenses after discharge
and expenses before admission will be
covered for this many days. If it
is related to cancer treatment, then
under Section B, if any organ transplant related to cancer has to be done, then
its expenses will also be covered in this section.
Next coverage is transportation
expenses if ambulance  If the policy is not used
or is not available, then
two trips can be made within ₹5000000 per trip and per day
and 10
trips are allowed in the entire policy. This much compensation can be given for
taking the patient to and from the hospital.
Other than ambulance, if
in any emergency or life threatening
condition, an ambulance related to cancer treatment is
used, then
hospitalization claim of ₹000 can also be made for the ambulance. The
final coverage that comes in
Section B is consumables, that is, the
non-medical items in List One of Annex One will
also be covered for cancer treatment in Section B.
Keep one thing in mind that all the
points of coverage that I have
told you under Section B
are associated with cancer treatment only and will cover only that treatment, just
like your normal health
insurance policy does. But
if there is any other medical condition apart from cancer, then it will
not be eligible for Section B claim. Now friends, it is the turn of Section
C.  This is the hospital cash. So far, the first
two sections that we have understood are:
Critical Illness cover in Section A,
Cancer treatment cover in Section B, and
Daily Cash Compensation called Hospital Cash, will be
given to the policy holder in Section C.
The amount of this compensation can be,
you have to choose it at the time of taking the policy itself.
You can choose the amount of compensation up to ₹5000000 per day
and the number of days can also be chosen from 30
days to 180 days. You have to choose
for how many days in a year
you want this coverage at the time of taking the policy itself. The
maximum
number of days per year will be the compensation, the
more your premium will
increase for the coverage of Section C. So, the first
coverage is Inpatient Hospital Cash, that is,
for the number of days a policy holder is
admitted, he will get that amount daily
for the maximum number of days that
you have chosen. You have to decide this daily till the time he remains admitted.
How much amount of premium do you have to pay?
Apart from this, you also get Prolong Hospitalization Cash, that is,
when the policy holder is hospitalized for 10 days or
more, then the
limit of ₹1000000 once in a year for
Prolong Hospitalization will be given to the
policy holder by the
insurance company for long hospitalization.
ICU Cash Benefit: If a policy holder
is admitted in ICU for treatment, then the
policy holder can claim double the amount of your daily cash limit for the number of days in ICU. The next
coverage is Accidental Hospitalization Cash
Benefit, that is, if a policy
holder is admitted in the hospital for treatment after an accident, then
he can claim two times the daily hospital cash limit for the number of
days he remains admitted in the hospital for treatment.
And if he has to be
admitted in ICU for accidental treatment, then the
policy holder will get double the amount of your daily hospital cash limit for
accidental ICU treatment. The maximum number
of days limit will depend on them.  The maximum
limit for which the premium has been paid in the entire year,
which they have chosen, out of 360 or
180 days, now
we have understood the three sections of this plan, section A
will cover critical needs, section B
will cover cancer treatment and section C will
cover hospital cash, out of these three
sections you must choose one section only
then you can take this plan,
apart from this you can also choose two sections
and all three sections,
but to take the plan
you must choose one section from A B C, you can
choose whatever coverage you want from these, after that there
is an optional section section D, in which
some surgeries can be covered, let us
understand them also once, in section D
you get three choices of coverage,
Classic, Supreme and Elite, Classic is the
option with the least coverage, there is
medium coverage in Supreme and
you will get the maximum coverage in Elite,
first of all some minor surgeries are covered in it,
which you will not get now  It is visible on the screen that
according to your variant which you have
chosen from Classic, Supreme and Elite,
how much coverage you will get is
visible on the screen right now. Along with this,
some major surgeries will also be covered, their
amount will also depend on your variant,
how much lump sum amount
you can claim per surgery. There is a
waiting period of 90 days for both minor and major surgeries, that is,
when you buy the policy and you have
chosen Section D, which is an optional cover, then
you will get coverage for them only after 90 days.
Apart from this,
coverage of post-operative physiotherapy is also included in it, that is, if
an operation is done and after that the
policy holder needs physiotherapy, then
its coverage can also be
taken under Section D. Apart from this,
ambulance coverage can also be
taken under Section D. After Section D, there is
another optional cover which comes under Section E,
that is personal accidental cover. You
can take this only along with Section A, that is, the critical illness section, in which the policy
holder's personal insurance of ₹ lakh  Accidental
insurance is available
if you have chosen Section B or Section C.
Now,
after understanding all the five sections, there are three base
sections from which you will have to choose
and two optional sections are Section D
and Section E. After understanding these, let us
also understand their waiting period once, after
how much time you will get coverage of which section.
First of all, let us understand the initial waiting
period once. If you
choose Section A for critical illness
coverage, then there will be a waiting period of 90 days, that is, if
any critical illness is diagnosed within the first 90 days, then
it will not be covered. If you choose Section B,
which covers cancer treatment, then there is a
waiting period of 90 days in that too.
If cancer is diagnosed within the first 90 days,
then the coverage of the policy will
not be applicable. There is a waiting period of 30 days for Section C for
hospital cash.  You will have to
wait only for 30 days, after that
if there is any hospitalization then the
daily cash amount can be claimed,
if a policy holder has any pre-exiting disease
then its waiting
period will be 48 months i.e. 4 years
and specific disease because it will
not be covered under section A because it covers only
critical illness, it will
not be covered under section B also because it
covers cancer,
you can take its coverage only for section C,
its waiting period for specific disease will be 24
months, so only after this much waiting period will the
eligibility for claim be made under this plan, so
friends, we understood this about Tata AAG
's critical Medicare plan, now if we have to take a
critical illness plan and we
finalize this plan, suppose and someone
explains this plan to us or
tries to sell us something, then we already
know what sections are there in this plan,
whose money we have to pay and what
coverage we need, which decisions  The
more clarity we take them, the more
satisfactorily
[Music] I
feel I have done that. So to show your love
and support, you
can like and share the video. If
you want to see similar information videos in the future, then do
subscribe to the channel.
If you
want to see very important information related to health insurance coverage for critical illness, then you can
see the complete information by clicking on this video.
I am Harvinder Singh. Now I take your
permission. I will get your permission in the next video. Till then,
take care of yourself, stay happy
and stay healthy. Jai Hind.